Hi Guys welcome back.
So now we're going to talk about those project trophy's activity and it is not as simple as it may sound.
I mean it cannot be assumed that once a project meets all the deadlines and the basic requirements are
delivered we can close a project.
It's a an activity you have to perform certain activities to close the project
not closing usually happen at the end of the project and deliverables are delivered.
Usually most of the companies will have certain set of activities a template kind of things you know
where they will have certain checkboxes and a project manager is responsible for making sure that all
the check boxes are checked.
So it's like you know checking that all the deliverables the code that document the test result because
it's not just the code you will have to alter or delivered the big document that Klarman document that
testing deserves the project management plan itself.
All of that can be part of your deliverables So you have to make sure that all of that is kind of baseline
and uploaded wherever it is needs to be uploaded usually your client will have you know certain procedures
and you need to follow them to deliver all the deliverables for all project you will have a charge called
or the Bluebeard's called so you need to make sure that all the Rs which are assigned to it are well
accounted for.
And now the team members should not use that called for charging.
So that has to be closed in your timesheet system you use.
So if somebody tried to charge it in that school they shouldn't be able to do that.
If you are using some vendor for any particular services you need to make sure that their building is
complete and their accounting is closed.
If there are certain activities which you need to perform like in-home demonstration of deliverables
or some kind of you know post-delivery feedback system with your stakeholders and user that should be
performed.
So all of that is part of your you know closing the project phase.
And yes it could be fees also because if so whether its a project or phase you have to follow the standard
guidelines for your organization to close it.
These are the inputs.
So we have project chart project management plan project documents and all the documents assumption
law business of us change log issue log lesson learned or just milestone List Project communication
quality control measurements quality reports requirement documentation risk registers board and yes
always remember that all projects may not have all of these documents.
Some off projects means there are certain documents which I think will be present in all the projects
like Lesson learned.
Register all the quality control measurement but its not necessary that all of these documents will
be always available in all the projects.
In fact Johns's are companies using one single document to record all of these things so they may have
one document where they will record assumptions issues and change logs.
All of that instead of having separate documents so don't bother if you don't see all of these documents
in your organization in your team.
But point is all of these will be discarded or at least most of them.
And then you have to accept deliverables business documents like business case benefit management plan
agreements procurement documentation in case of a vendor.
If there's no problem then chances are you won't have this.
And then of course the organizational process such because as I said you will always have some kind
of standard process or template.
Unless you are a new organization or a startup and for tools and techniques you will have expert jazzmen
data analysis for document analysis regression analysis and analysis variance analysis.
And of course the meetings to meet with the stakeholders and the users and to conclude the project and
for outport we have the project document.
So lesson learned is to say as I said earlier in one of the videos that we did.
Lesson learned.
Just in with all the project so you will have to make updates to this and then the final product service
or whatever you are expected to deliver.
Final Report.
Organizational processes are sex objects and these other applications.
So as a result of a project you may have to the following parties will be impacted.
So customers are of course the primary impacted parties because whatever you are delivering chances
are they are the primary end users.
They are going to be consumers so they are.
They will be impacted.
And then we have the documents and Mamadu factor.
So is project documents along with the procurement documentation.
But is that is kind of you know depends upon the project but customers they will be impacted member
I mean no matter what you do if you are doing something in a project they are going to be impacted.
And usually we expect that the impact will be positive but sometimes it could be negative like they
may have to do some additional processing for them compliances.
Government may come up with some new law.
Now as far as business is concerned that's not their primary requirement.
They have to you know do that.
So it will increase their time and effort.
So in that case the impact would be negative.
But yes a lot of time the impact would be positive.
So that's it for now for this section in the next section.
We were talking about the project school management which is vital for the success of any project and
that is again very important and we'll go to a lot of important stuff like WPA and those kind of things.
So stay tuned.
Thank you.